Mahip Kaushal

Full Stack Developer

A software engineer with prime focus on Web Applications. I have worked on design/esthetic intensive Frontends, Analytics & data-driven Backends and more.

With proficiency in multiple technologies and rich experience, I am determined to provide value to the Organizations and Clients I work for.

EXPERIENCE

Nickelfox, Noida — Full Stack Developer

June 2018 - PRESENT

Technology stack - PHP, Node Js, React, Vue, Bootstrap, Shopify, AWS, CircleCI, Asana, Git

- Design and develop websites from concept to completion.
- Architect, design and develop rich responsive consumerfacing web applications.
- Maintain multiple projects in a fast-paced, professional environment.
- Coordinate with design team to achieve pragmatic design for implementation.
- Work closely with various clients on customized MVP products by following the agile methodologies.
- Setup and Maintaining Cloud services in AWS.
- Handle DevOps, CI/CD related tasks.
- Code review, Technical research, Documentation.
- Provide technical support to peers and Interns.
- Involved in Front-End Developer, Back-End Developer and Intern hiring process.

Steelmint Info Services, Raipur — Web Developer

June 2017 - June 2018

Technology stack - PHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MySQL

- Designed and developed organization's website frontend and backend.
- Developed, Maintained and customized web CRM applications for organization internal use.
- Developed Rest-APIs for mobile app.
- Managed and provide guidance to other team members

Tailmill, Noida — Lead Software Engineer

January 2016 - February 2017

Technology stack - PHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MySQL, OpenCart

- Developed, Maintained and customized web CRM applications for organization internal use.
- Managed and provide guidance to other team members
- Responsible for hiring new member in the IT team

Phone: +91 704 220 2385

Email: mahipkaushal2905@gmail.com
Website: https://mahipkaushal.com

LinkedIn: https://linkedin.com/in/mahip-kaushal

GitHub: https://github.com/Mahipkaushal

Programming Languages

- JavaScript
- Node Js
- PHP 5.x/7.x
- HTML 5
- CSS, SASS

Frameworks/Libraries

- React
- Vue
- Bootstrap 4
- Webpack
- Express / Node JS
- Laravel
- Shopify
- OpenCart
- JS Template Engine (EJS, Mustache,)

Databases

- MongoDB
- MySQL

Platforms and Tools

- AWS (EC2, S3, RDS, Route 53 etc.)
- DNS Management
- Git
- Circle CI
- Asana
- Postman
- Adobe Photoshop CS6

Tailmill, Noida — Full Stack Developer

May 2014 - December 2016

Technology stack - PHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MySQL, OpenCart

- Designed and developed organization's website frontend and backend.
- Developed, Maintained and customized web CRM applications for organization internal use.
- Responsible for hiring new member in the IT team

PROJECTS

HopBike — Restful APIs

Duration - March 2020 - Present

Technology stack - Node.js (Express), AWS, Circle CI

Scope- HopBike is a self-drive mobility service running on 100% electric scooters. Rent the scooters via app, and hop to your destination.

Roles

- Planning, architecture and development of Restful APIs using Node Js.
- Designed and architect database in MongoDB.
- Take care of build pipeline and the deployment to staging and production environments.
- Take part in routine discussions with remote collaborators and team members.
- Provide technical support to frontend engineers for consistent development of UI.
- Preliminary documentation and rundown for the Architecture of Backend Rest APIs.

HealthyKeys (Admin Portal) — Web Application | Project Link: https://admin.healthykeys.co/

Duration - January 2020 - March 2020

Technology stack - HTML, Next.js, JavaScript, CSS, PHP (Laravel), CircleCI, AWS S3

Roles

- Developed entire admin portal in React from scratch.
- Implemented Rest APIs for admin portal.
- Setup and Configured the deployment, staging and production environments pipeline.
- Setup and Configured CircleCl for Continuous Development and Integration.
- Configured AWS EC2 Server with SSL for web application hosting.

Franengage (Admin Portal) — Web Application | Project Link: http://dev.admin.franengage.com.s3-website-us-east-

1.amazonaws.com/

Duration - December 2019 - February 2020

Technology stack - HTML, React, JavaScript, CSS, CircleCI, AWS S3

Scope – The Franengage is a Franchise Platform. Different franchise companies can subscribe to this platform and provide their prospects a way to find all the information about their Franchise via mobile Applications.

Roles

- Developed entire admin portal in React from scratch.
- Setup and Configured the deployment, staging and production environments pipeline.
- Setup and Configured CircleCI for Continuous Development and Integration.
- Configured AWS S3 bucket for web application hosting.

Scopeworker — Brochureware, Dynamic | Project Link: https://scopeworker.com/

Duration - March 2019 - January 2020

Technology stack - HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, WordPress

Scope - Scopeworker is an enterprise B2B SaaS marketplace

Scopeworker provides innovative solutions and, ultimately, having a positive efficiency impact for buyers, suppliers and workers using the Scopeworker platform.

The main web application is the Website implemented in WordPress from scratch using ThemeCo Pro.

Roles

- Develop the Frontend from the designs available on Zeplin.
- Created PHP and JavaScript scripts to collect form data from website and store it into Google Sheet.

GGHS Digital Wallet Admin Portal — Restful APIs

Duration - June 2019 - October 2019

Technology stack - Express / Node JS

Scope - Generali Global Health Services (GGHS) is a leading specialist international health administration services company based in Toronto, Canada, and worldwide. GGHS provide International and Global Medical Networks, Medical Case Management, International Medical Claims Management, Medical Cost Containment, Medical Assistance and Customer Care Services, as well as a range of other third party administrative and support services. These enable Generali companies (as well as other corporate clients) to provide their clients and members with access to world-class medical care wherever they are in the world, all delivered with the exceptional service, care and support people expect from the Generali brand.

Roles

- Planning, architecture and development of Restful APIs using Node Js.
- Designed and architect database in MongoDB.
- Take care of build pipeline and the deployment to staging and production environments.
- Take part in routine discussions with remote collaborators and team members.
- Provide technical support to frontend engineers for consistent development of UI.
- Preliminary documentation and rundown for the Architecture of Backend Rest APIs.

Aviteur — Brochureware, Dynamic | Project Link: https://aviteur.com/

Duration - January 2019 - April 2019

Technology stack - HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Shopify

Scope - A static website to market the Aviteur products.

Roles

- Set up the staging and production deployment pipeline
- Set up the Shopify Store.
- Configure the GoDaddy domain with the Shopify DNS.

Unleash live — Brochureware, Static | Project Link: https://unleashlive.com/

Duration - August 2018 - November 2018

Technology stack - JavaScript, HTML, Webpack, Handlebars, CSS, AWS, S3, Circle CI

Scope - Unleash live is a cloud-based software platform ingesting live video and imagery applying real time A.I. analytics to improve instant decision making.

Roles

- Researched and tested the JavaScript libraries for integrating in the static website.
- Research on different types of animations possible with third party libraries.
- Implemented the website from available designs.

GGHS Passkit Web App — Web Application

Duration - September 2018 - October 2018

Technology stack - Vue JS, Node Js

Scope - A web application to generate Passes for Apple Wallet

Roles

- Gather and understand the requirement from clients.
- Design and architect the frontend and backend of the application.
- Design and develop the product Frontend in Vue.
- Design and develop the product Backend in Node Js.

Nickelfox Technologies Pvt. Ltd. — Brochureware, Static | Project Link: https://nickelfox.com/

Duration - July 2018 - September 2018

Technology stack - JavaScript, HTML, Webpack, Handlebars, CSS, AWS, S3, Circle CI

Roles

• Developed the Website from the designs available on Zeplin.

Rickie Ashman Portfolio — Web Application | Project Link: https://rickieashman.com/

Duration - April 2018 - July 2018

Technology stack - Vue, PHP, Laravel

Scope - Rickie Ashman is a Creative Director and Strategist, based in Los Angeles, with a talent for linking Western brands with Asian aesthetics and marketing practices.

This project includes website and the admin panel

Roles

- Gather and understand the requirement from clients.
- Design and architect the frontend and backend of the application.
- Design and develop the product Frontend in Vue.
- Design and develop the product Backend in Laravel.
- Design and develop the admin panel to manage client's blogs.
- Design and develop the database using MySQL.

Steelmint — Web Application | Project Link: https://steelmint.com/

Duration - June 2017 - June 2018

Technology stack - PHP, Laravel, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery

Scope - SteelMint is one-of-its-kind Steel research, analysis and consultancy company based in India.

This project includes website and the admin panel

Roles

- Design and architect the frontend and backend of the application.
- Design and develop the Frontend in HTML, CSS, Javascript, Bootstrap.
- Design and develop the product Backend in PHP.
- Design and develop the database using MySQL.
- Created Restful APIs for mobile application in Laravel.

Mahipkaushal.com — Web Application | Project Link: https://mahipkaushal.com/

Duration - May 2016 - June 2016

Technology stack - PHP (Laravel), HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, MySQL

Scope - Portfolio Website

This project includes website and the admin panel

Roles

- Design and architect the frontend and backend of the application.
- Design and develop the Frontend in HTML, CSS, JavaScript.
- Design and develop the product Backend in PHP (Laravel).
- Design and develop the database using MySQL.

Tailmill — Web Application | Project Link: http://www.tailmill.com/

Duration - May 2014 - Feb 2017

Technology stack - PHP, OpenCart, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, MySQL

Scope - Tailmill is a cloud-based auto-replenishment platform to automate the purchase of your regularly consumed products.

This project includes website and the admin panel

Roles

- Design and architect the frontend and backend of the application.
- Design and develop the Frontend in HTML, CSS, JavaScript.
- Design and develop the product Backend in PHP.
- Design and develop the database using MySQL.

EDUCATION

2013 Bachelor of Technology (C.S.E.) — Institute Technology Guru Ghasidas University, Bilaspur, C.G.

2008 *Intermediate (12th)* — Kendriya Vidyalaya, Jagdalpur, C.G. (CBSE)

2006 High School (10th) — Vidhyodaya Hr. Sec. School, Jagdalpur, C.G. (CGBSE)